[
    {
        "question": "وَأَبَارِيقَ",
        "answer": "and jugs",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 3,
        "tlit": "wa-abārīqa",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " بِأَكْوَابٍ وَأَبَارِيقَ",
        "rootWord": "أَبَارِيق",
        "rootWordType": "noun",
        "wazn": "أَبَارِيق",
        "waznEnglish": "jugs, pitchers",
        "waznTlit": "abārīq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَوَآبَاؤُنَا",
        "answer": "And also our fathers",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 10,
        "tlit": "awaābāunā",
        "frequency": "117",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَوَآبَاؤُنَا الْأَوَّلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آبَاء",
        "waznEnglish": "forefathers, fathers, parents",
        "waznTlit": "ābā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَأْثِيمًا",
        "answer": "sinful (speech)",
        "pcklId": "47",
        "rootWordId": 16,
        "tlit": "tathīman",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسْمَعُونَ فِيهَا لَغْوًا وَلَا تَأْثِيمًا",
        "rootWord": "أ ث م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَأْثِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "sin, recrimination",
        "waznTlit": "tathīm",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أُجَاجًا",
        "answer": "salty",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 17,
        "tlit": "ujājan",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "70",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ نَشَاءُ جَعَلْنَاهُ أُجَاجًا فَلَوْلَا تَشْكُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ج ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ج ج",
        "waznEnglish": "salty, bitter",
        "waznTlit": "hamza jīm jīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرِينَ",
        "answer": "the later (people)",
        "pcklId": "141",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhirīna",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَلِيلٌ مِنَ الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرِينَ",
        "answer": "the later people",
        "pcklId": "142",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhirīna",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَثُلَّةٌ مِنَ الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْآخِرِينَ",
        "answer": "and the later people",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "wal-ākhirīna",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "49",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " قُلْ إِنَّ الْأَوَّلِينَ وَالْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "314",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا وَقَعَتِ الْوَاقِعَةُ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "315",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا رُجَّتِ الْأَرْضُ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَئِذَا",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "316",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "a-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَقُولُونَ أَئِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "317",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "83",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَوْلَا إِذَا بَلَغَتِ الْحُلْقُومَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَرْضُ",
        "answer": "the earth",
        "pcklId": "415",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "l-arḍu",
        "frequency": "461",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا رُجَّتِ الْأَرْضُ رَجًّا",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَآكِلُونَ",
        "answer": "Will surely eat",
        "pcklId": "107",
        "rootWordId": 54,
        "tlit": "laākilūna",
        "frequency": "109",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لَآكِلُونَ مِنْ شَجَرٍ مِنْ زَقُّومٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ك ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَاكِلُون",
        "waznEnglish": "those who eat",
        "waznTlit": "ākilūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "520",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا قِيلًا سَلَامًا سَلَامًا",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "521",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "79",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَمَسُّهُ إِلَّا الْمُطَهَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "which",
        "pcklId": "1280",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "68",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ الْمَاءَ الَّذِي تَشْرَبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّتِي",
        "answer": "which",
        "pcklId": "1281",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "allatī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "71",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ النَّارَ الَّتِي تُورُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "for",
        "pcklId": "664",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَمَجْمُوعُونَ إِلَىٰ مِيقَاتِ يَوْمٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَيْهِ",
        "answer": "to him",
        "pcklId": "665",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilayhi",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "85",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَحْنُ أَقْرَبُ إِلَيْهِ مِنْكُمْ وَلَٰكِنْ لَا تُبْصِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "or",
        "pcklId": "120",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": "137",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "59",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ تَخْلُقُونَهُ أَمْ نَحْنُ الْخَالِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "or",
        "pcklId": "121",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": "137",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "64",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ تَزْرَعُونَهُ أَمْ نَحْنُ الزَّارِعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "or",
        "pcklId": "122",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": "137",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "69",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَنْزَلْتُمُوهُ مِنَ الْمُزْنِ أَمْ نَحْنُ الْمُنْزِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "or",
        "pcklId": "123",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": "137",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "72",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَنْشَأْتُمْ شَجَرَتَهَا أَمْ نَحْنُ الْمُنْشِئُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "Then",
        "pcklId": "52",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "fa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "88",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا إِنْ كَانَ مِنَ الْمُقَرَّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Conditional particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "And",
        "pcklId": "53",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "wa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "90",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا إِنْ كَانَ مِنْ أَصْحَابِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Conditional particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "But",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "wa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "92",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا إِنْ كَانَ مِنَ الْمُكَذِّبِينَ الضَّالِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Conditional particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "the former (people)",
        "pcklId": "48",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalīna",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُلَّةٌ مِنَ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "the former people",
        "pcklId": "49",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalīna",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُلَّةٌ مِنَ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "the former",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalīna",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "49",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " قُلْ إِنَّ الْأَوَّلِينَ وَالْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُولَىٰ",
        "answer": "the first",
        "pcklId": "51",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-ūlā",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "62",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ عَلِمْتُمُ النَّشْأَةَ الْأُولَىٰ فَلَوْلَا تَذَكَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلُونَ",
        "answer": "former",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalūna",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَوَآبَاؤُنَا الْأَوَّلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْبَثًّا",
        "answer": "dispersing",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 96,
        "tlit": "munbathan",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَانَتْ هَبَاءً مُنْبَثًّا",
        "rootWord": "ب ث ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّنبَثّ",
        "waznEnglish": "and dispersing",
        "waznTlit": "munbath",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُبَدِّلَ",
        "answer": "We (will) change",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 106,
        "tlit": "nubaddila",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "61",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَىٰ أَنْ نُبَدِّلَ أَمْثَالَكُمْ وَنُنْشِئَكُمْ فِي مَا لَا تَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب د ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَدَّلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to change",
        "waznTlit": "baddala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَارِدٍ",
        "answer": "cool",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 113,
        "tlit": "bāridin",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا بَارِدٍ وَلَا كَرِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ر د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَارِد",
        "waznEnglish": "cool[ness]",
        "waznTlit": "bārid",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَبُسَّتِ",
        "answer": "And will be crumbled",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 123,
        "tlit": "wabussati",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبُسَّتِ الْجِبَالُ بَسًّا",
        "rootWord": "ب س س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُسَّتِ",
        "waznEnglish": "to crumble, to crush",
        "waznTlit": "bussati",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَسًّا",
        "answer": "(with awful) crumbling",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 123,
        "tlit": "bassan",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبُسَّتِ الْجِبَالُ بَسًّا",
        "rootWord": "ب س س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَسّ",
        "waznEnglish": "And will be crumbled",
        "waznTlit": "bass",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُبْصِرُونَ",
        "answer": "you (do) not see",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "tub'ṣirūna",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "85",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَحْنُ أَقْرَبُ إِلَيْهِ مِنْكُمْ وَلَٰكِنْ لَا تُبْصِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبْصَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "abṣara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبُطُونَ",
        "answer": "the bellies",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 136,
        "tlit": "l-buṭūna",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَالِئُونَ مِنْهَا الْبُطُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ط ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَطْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) concealed",
        "waznTlit": "baṭn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "answer": "surely be resurrected",
        "pcklId": "64",
        "rootWordId": 137,
        "tlit": "lamabʿūthūna",
        "frequency": "67",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَقُولُونَ أَئِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّبْعُوثُون",
        "waznEnglish": "We revived you",
        "waznTlit": "mabʿūthūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبْكَارًا",
        "answer": "virgins",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 151,
        "tlit": "abkāran",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلْنَاهُنَّ أَبْكَارًا",
        "rootWord": "ب ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "and (in) the morning",
        "waznTlit": "bik'r",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَلَغَتِ",
        "answer": "it reaches",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 157,
        "tlit": "balaghati",
        "frequency": "77",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "83",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَوْلَا إِذَا بَلَغَتِ الْحُلْقُومَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ل غ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَلَغَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reach",
        "waznTlit": "balagha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيْنَكُمُ",
        "answer": "among you",
        "pcklId": "282",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "baynakumu",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "60",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " نَحْنُ قَدَّرْنَا بَيْنَكُمُ الْمَوْتَ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمَسْبُوقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "bayn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَتْرَابًا",
        "answer": "equals in age",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 179,
        "tlit": "atrāban",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عُرُبًا أَتْرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتْرَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "well-matched",
        "waznTlit": "atrāb",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُرَابًا",
        "answer": "dust",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 179,
        "tlit": "turāban",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَقُولُونَ أَئِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تُرَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "well-matched",
        "waznTlit": "turāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُتْرَفِينَ",
        "answer": "indulging in affluence",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 180,
        "tlit": "mut'rafīna",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا قَبْلَ ذَٰلِكَ مُتْرَفِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُتْرَفِين",
        "waznEnglish": "luxury they were given",
        "waznTlit": "mut'rafīn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ثَلَاثَةً",
        "answer": "three",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 206,
        "tlit": "thalāthatan",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُنْتُمْ أَزْوَاجًا ثَلَاثَةً",
        "rootWord": "ث ل ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ثَلَٰثَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(is the) third",
        "waznTlit": "thalāthat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ثُلَّةٌ",
        "answer": "A company",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 207,
        "tlit": "thullatun",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُلَّةٌ مِنَ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ث ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ث ل ل",
        "waznEnglish": "A company",
        "waznTlit": "thā lām lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ثُلَّةٌ",
        "answer": "A company",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 207,
        "tlit": "thullatun",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُلَّةٌ مِنَ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ث ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ث ل ل",
        "waznEnglish": "A company",
        "waznTlit": "thā lām lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَثُلَّةٌ",
        "answer": "And a company",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 207,
        "tlit": "wathullatun",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَثُلَّةٌ مِنَ الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ث ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ث ل ل",
        "waznEnglish": "A company",
        "waznTlit": "thā lām lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجِبَالُ",
        "answer": "the mountains",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 219,
        "tlit": "l-jibālu",
        "frequency": "41",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبُسَّتِ الْجِبَالُ بَسًّا",
        "rootWord": "ج ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَبَل",
        "waznEnglish": "hill",
        "waznTlit": "jabal",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَحِيمٍ",
        "answer": "(in) Hellfire",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "jaḥīmin",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "94",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَصْلِيَةُ جَحِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَزَاءً",
        "answer": "A reward",
        "pcklId": "109",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "jazāan",
        "frequency": "118",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " جَزَاءً بِمَا كَانُوا يَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "avail",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَجَعَلْنَاهُنَّ",
        "answer": "And We have made them",
        "pcklId": "293",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "fajaʿalnāhunna",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلْنَاهُنَّ أَبْكَارًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَجَعَلْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "We (would) surely, make it",
        "pcklId": "294",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "lajaʿalnāhu",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "65",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ نَشَاءُ لَجَعَلْنَاهُ حُطَامًا فَظَلْتُمْ تَفَكَّهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَعَلْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "We (could) make it",
        "pcklId": "295",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "jaʿalnāhu",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "70",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ نَشَاءُ جَعَلْنَاهُ أُجَاجًا فَلَوْلَا تَشْكُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَعَلْنَاهَا",
        "answer": "have made it",
        "pcklId": "296",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "jaʿalnāhā",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "73",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " نَحْنُ جَعَلْنَاهَا تَذْكِرَةً وَمَتَاعًا لِلْمُقْوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَجْعَلُونَ",
        "answer": "And you make",
        "pcklId": "297",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "watajʿalūna",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "82",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَجْعَلُونَ رِزْقَكُمْ أَنَّكُمْ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمَجْمُوعُونَ",
        "answer": "Surely, will be gathered",
        "pcklId": "127",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "lamajmūʿūna",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لَمَجْمُوعُونَ إِلَىٰ مِيقَاتِ يَوْمٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّجْمُوع",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "majmūʿ",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَّاتِ",
        "answer": "Gardens",
        "pcklId": "107",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "jannāti",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي جَنَّاتِ النَّعِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَنَّتُ",
        "answer": "and a Garden",
        "pcklId": "108",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "wajannatu",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "89",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَوْحٌ وَرَيْحَانٌ وَجَنَّتُ نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَدِيثِ",
        "answer": "statement",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 297,
        "tlit": "l-ḥadīthi",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "81",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَبِهَٰذَا الْحَدِيثِ أَنْتُمْ مُدْهِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح د ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَدِيث",
        "waznEnglish": "Do you tell them",
        "waznTlit": "ḥadīth",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَحْرُثُونَ",
        "answer": "you sow",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 302,
        "tlit": "taḥruthūna",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "63",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمْ مَا تَحْرُثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ر ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَحْرُثُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to sow",
        "waznTlit": "taḥruthu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَحْرُومُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) deprived",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 312,
        "tlit": "maḥrūmūna",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "67",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ نَحْنُ مَحْرُومُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَحْرُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "He has forbidden",
        "waznTlit": "maḥrūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "حُطَامًا",
        "answer": "debris",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 334,
        "tlit": "ḥuṭāman",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "65",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ نَشَاءُ لَجَعَلْنَاهُ حُطَامًا فَظَلْتُمْ تَفَكَّهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ط م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حُطَٰم",
        "waznEnglish": "lest not crush you",
        "waznTlit": "ḥuṭām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَقُّ",
        "answer": "(is the) truth",
        "pcklId": "268",
        "rootWordId": 344,
        "tlit": "ḥaqqu",
        "frequency": "287",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "95",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ هَٰذَا لَهُوَ حَقُّ الْيَقِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَقّ",
        "waznEnglish": "deserved ",
        "waznTlit": "ḥaqq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحُلْقُومَ",
        "answer": "the throat",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 347,
        "tlit": "l-ḥul'qūma",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "83",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَوْلَا إِذَا بَلَغَتِ الْحُلْقُومَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حُلْقُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "shave",
        "waznTlit": "ḥul'qūm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَحَمِيمٍ",
        "answer": "and scalding water",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 355,
        "tlit": "waḥamīmin",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي سَمُومٍ وَحَمِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "boiling water",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَمِيمِ",
        "answer": "the scalding water",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 355,
        "tlit": "l-ḥamīmi",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "54",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَشَارِبُونَ عَلَيْهِ مِنَ الْحَمِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ح م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "boiling water",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَمِيمٍ",
        "answer": "(the) scalding water",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 355,
        "tlit": "ḥamīmin",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "93",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَنُزُلٌ مِنْ حَمِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "boiling water",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَحْمُومٍ",
        "answer": "black smoke",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 355,
        "tlit": "yaḥmūmin",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَظِلٍّ مِنْ يَحْمُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَحْمُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "boiling water",
        "waznTlit": "yaḥmūm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحِنْثِ",
        "answer": "the sin",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 357,
        "tlit": "l-ḥinthi",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يُصِرُّونَ عَلَى الْحِنْثِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ح ن ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حِنث",
        "waznEnglish": "break (your) oath",
        "waznTlit": "ḥinth",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَحُورٌ",
        "answer": "And fair ones",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 367,
        "tlit": "waḥūrun",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَحُورٌ عِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ح و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حُور",
        "waznEnglish": "he would return",
        "waznTlit": "ḥūr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "حِينَئِذٍ",
        "answer": "(at) that time",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 380,
        "tlit": "ḥīna-idhin",
        "frequency": "35",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "84",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْتُمْ حِينَئِذٍ تَنْظُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ح ي ن",
        "waznEnglish": "a period",
        "waznTlit": "ḥā yā nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَخْضُودٍ",
        "answer": "thornless",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 414,
        "tlit": "makhḍūdin",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي سِدْرٍ مَخْضُودٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ض د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خ ض د",
        "waznEnglish": "thornless",
        "waznTlit": "khā ḍād dāl",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَافِضَةٌ",
        "answer": "Bringing down",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 423,
        "tlit": "khāfiḍatun",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " خَافِضَةٌ رَافِعَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "خ ف ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَافِضَة",
        "waznEnglish": "And lower",
        "waznTlit": "khāfiḍat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُخَلَّدُونَ",
        "answer": "immortal",
        "pcklId": "86",
        "rootWordId": 426,
        "tlit": "mukhalladūna",
        "frequency": "87",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَطُوفُ عَلَيْهِمْ وِلْدَانٌ مُخَلَّدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّخَلَّدُون",
        "waznEnglish": "and he will abide forever",
        "waznTlit": "mukhalladūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form II) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْنَاكُمْ",
        "answer": "[We] created you",
        "pcklId": "151",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqnākum",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "57",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " نَحْنُ خَلَقْنَاكُمْ فَلَوْلَا تُصَدِّقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَخْلُقُونَهُ",
        "answer": "who create it",
        "pcklId": "152",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "takhluqūnahu",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "59",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ تَخْلُقُونَهُ أَمْ نَحْنُ الْخَالِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْخَالِقُونَ",
        "answer": "the Creators",
        "pcklId": "256",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "l-khāliqūna",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "59",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ تَخْلُقُونَهُ أَمْ نَحْنُ الْخَالِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَٰلِق",
        "waznEnglish": "created you",
        "waznTlit": "khāliq",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَخَيَّرُونَ",
        "answer": "they select",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "yatakhayyarūna",
        "frequency": "196",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَاكِهَةٍ مِمَّا يَتَخَيَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَتَخَيَّرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to select, to choose",
        "waznTlit": "yatakhayyaru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُدْهِنُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) indifferent",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 492,
        "tlit": "mud'hinūna",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "81",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَبِهَٰذَا الْحَدِيثِ أَنْتُمْ مُدْهِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د ه ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّدْهِنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "you should compromise",
        "waznTlit": "mud'hinūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الدِّينِ",
        "answer": "(of) Judgment",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "l-dīni",
        "frequency": "101",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا نُزُلُهُمْ يَوْمَ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "dīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَدِينِينَ",
        "answer": "to be recompensed",
        "pcklId": "100",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "madīnīna",
        "frequency": "101",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "86",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَوْلَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ غَيْرَ مَدِينِينَ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَدِينِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "madīnīn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَذَكَّرُونَ",
        "answer": "you take heed",
        "pcklId": "147",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "tadhakkarūna",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "62",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ عَلِمْتُمُ النَّشْأَةَ الْأُولَىٰ فَلَوْلَا تَذَكَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَذَكَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to receive admonition",
        "waznTlit": "tadhakkara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَذْكِرَةً",
        "answer": "a reminder",
        "pcklId": "277",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "tadhkiratan",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "73",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " نَحْنُ جَعَلْنَاهَا تَذْكِرَةً وَمَتَاعًا لِلْمُقْوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَذْكِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "tadhkirat",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَفَرَأَيْتُمْ",
        "answer": "Do you see",
        "pcklId": "221",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "afara-aytum",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "58",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمْ مَا تُمْنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَفَرَأَيْتُمْ",
        "answer": "And do you see",
        "pcklId": "222",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "afara-aytum",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "63",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمْ مَا تَحْرُثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ",
        "answer": "Do you see",
        "pcklId": "223",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "afara-aytumu",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "68",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ الْمَاءَ الَّذِي تَشْرَبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ",
        "answer": "Do you see",
        "pcklId": "224",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "afara-aytumu",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "71",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ النَّارَ الَّتِي تُورُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "(of) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "858",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "74",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّ",
        "answer": "(the) Lord",
        "pcklId": "859",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "80",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " تَنْزِيلٌ مِنْ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "(of) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "860",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "96",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رُجَّتِ",
        "answer": "will be shaken",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 533,
        "tlit": "rujjati",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا رُجَّتِ الْأَرْضُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ج ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رُجَّتِ",
        "waznEnglish": "to shake",
        "waznTlit": "rujjati",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَجًّا",
        "answer": "(with) a shaking",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 533,
        "tlit": "rajjan",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " رَجًّا",
        "rootWord": "ر ج ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَجّ",
        "waznEnglish": "will be shaken",
        "waznTlit": "rajj",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرْجِعُونَهَا",
        "answer": "Bring it back",
        "pcklId": "71",
        "rootWordId": 536,
        "tlit": "tarjiʿūnahā",
        "frequency": "104",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "87",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " تَرْجِعُونَهَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ج ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَجَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to return",
        "waznTlit": "rajaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رِزْقَكُمْ",
        "answer": "your provision",
        "pcklId": "111",
        "rootWordId": 552,
        "tlit": "riz'qakum",
        "frequency": "123",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "82",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَجْعَلُونَ رِزْقَكُمْ أَنَّكُمْ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ز ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رِزْق",
        "waznEnglish": "We have provided them",
        "waznTlit": "riz'q",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَافِعَةٌ",
        "answer": "raising up",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 573,
        "tlit": "rāfiʿatun",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " خَافِضَةٌ رَافِعَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّافِعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and We raised",
        "waznTlit": "rāfiʿat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَرْفُوعَةٍ",
        "answer": "raised",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 573,
        "tlit": "marfūʿatin",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفُرُشٍ مَرْفُوعَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّرْفُوعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and We raised",
        "waznTlit": "marfūʿat",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَرَوْحٌ",
        "answer": "Then rest",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 599,
        "tlit": "farawḥun",
        "frequency": "57",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "89",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَوْحٌ وَرَيْحَانٌ وَجَنَّتُ نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر و ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّوْح",
        "waznEnglish": "you bring them in",
        "waznTlit": "rawḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَرَيْحَانٌ",
        "answer": "and bounty",
        "pcklId": "56",
        "rootWordId": 599,
        "tlit": "warayḥānun",
        "frequency": "57",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "89",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَوْحٌ وَرَيْحَانٌ وَجَنَّتُ نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر و ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّيْحَان",
        "waznEnglish": "you bring them in",
        "waznTlit": "rayḥān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَزْرَعُونَهُ",
        "answer": "cause it to grow",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 617,
        "tlit": "tazraʿūnahu",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "64",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ تَزْرَعُونَهُ أَمْ نَحْنُ الزَّارِعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ز ر ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَزْرَعُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to plant, to sow",
        "waznTlit": "tazraʿu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الزَّارِعُونَ",
        "answer": "the Ones Who grow",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 617,
        "tlit": "l-zāriʿūna",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "64",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ تَزْرَعُونَهُ أَمْ نَحْنُ الزَّارِعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ز ر ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَّٰرِعُون",
        "waznEnglish": "You will sow",
        "waznTlit": "zāriʿūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "زَقُّومٍ",
        "answer": "Zaqqum",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 623,
        "tlit": "zaqqūmin",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لَآكِلُونَ مِنْ شَجَرٍ مِنْ زَقُّومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ز ق م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ز ق م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) Zaqqum",
        "waznTlit": "zāy qāf mīm",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَزْوَاجًا",
        "answer": "kinds",
        "pcklId": "70",
        "rootWordId": 638,
        "tlit": "azwājan",
        "frequency": "81",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُنْتُمْ أَزْوَاجًا ثَلَاثَةً",
        "rootWord": "ز و ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَوْج",
        "waznEnglish": "We married her to you",
        "waznTlit": "zawj",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَبِّحْ",
        "answer": "So glorify",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "fasabbiḥ",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "74",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبَّحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to glorify, to praise",
        "waznTlit": "sabbaḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَبِّحْ",
        "answer": "So glorify",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "fasabbiḥ",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "96",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبَّحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to glorify, to praise",
        "waznTlit": "sabbaḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالسَّابِقُونَ",
        "answer": "And the foremost",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 655,
        "tlit": "wal-sābiqūna",
        "frequency": "37",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالسَّابِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَابِق",
        "waznEnglish": "has preceded you",
        "waznTlit": "sābiq",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّابِقُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) the foremost",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 655,
        "tlit": "l-sābiqūna",
        "frequency": "37",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " السَّابِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَابِق",
        "waznEnglish": "has preceded you",
        "waznTlit": "sābiq",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِمَسْبُوقِينَ",
        "answer": "(are) outrun",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 655,
        "tlit": "bimasbūqīna",
        "frequency": "37",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "60",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " نَحْنُ قَدَّرْنَا بَيْنَكُمُ الْمَوْتَ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمَسْبُوقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَسْبُوقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "has preceded you",
        "waznTlit": "masbūqīn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "سِدْرٍ",
        "answer": "lote trees",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 672,
        "tlit": "sid'rin",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي سِدْرٍ مَخْضُودٍ",
        "rootWord": "س د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سِدْر",
        "waznEnglish": "lote trees",
        "waznTlit": "sid'r",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سُرُرٍ",
        "answer": "thrones",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 681,
        "tlit": "sururin",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَىٰ سُرُرٍ مَوْضُونَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُرُر",
        "waznEnglish": "pleasing",
        "waznTlit": "surur",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَسْكُوبٍ",
        "answer": "poured forth",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 705,
        "tlit": "maskūbin",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَاءٍ مَسْكُوبٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ك ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ك ب",
        "waznEnglish": "poured forth",
        "waznTlit": "sīn kāf bā",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَلَامًا",
        "answer": "Peace",
        "pcklId": "65",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "salāman",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا قِيلًا سَلَامًا",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَلَٰم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "salām",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَلَامًا",
        "answer": "Peace",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "salāman",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " سَلَامًا",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَلَٰم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "salām",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَلَامٌ",
        "answer": "Then, peace",
        "pcklId": "67",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "fasalāmun",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "91",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَلَامٌ لَكَ مِنْ أَصْحَابِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَلَٰم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "salām",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْمَعُونَ",
        "answer": "they will hear",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 722,
        "tlit": "yasmaʿūna",
        "frequency": "185",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسْمَعُونَ فِيهَا لَغْوًا وَلَا تَأْثِيمًا",
        "rootWord": "س م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمِعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to hear, to listen",
        "waznTlit": "samiʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَمُومٍ",
        "answer": "scorching fire",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 724,
        "tlit": "samūmin",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي سَمُومٍ وَحَمِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "س م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) eye",
        "waznTlit": "samūm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِاسْمِ",
        "answer": "(the) name",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "bi-is'mi",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "74",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْم",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "is'm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِاسْمِ",
        "answer": "(the) name",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "bi-is'mi",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "96",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْم",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "is'm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَشْأَمَةِ",
        "answer": "(of) the left",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 752,
        "tlit": "l-mashamati",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَصْحَابُ الْمَشْأَمَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ش أ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش أ م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the left",
        "waznTlit": "shīn hamza mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَشْأَمَةِ",
        "answer": "(of) the left",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 752,
        "tlit": "l-mashamati",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَصْحَابُ الْمَشْأَمَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ش أ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش أ م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the left",
        "waznTlit": "shīn hamza mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَجَرٍ",
        "answer": "(the) tree",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 757,
        "tlit": "shajarin",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَآكِلُونَ مِنْ شَجَرٍ مِنْ زَقُّومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَجَر",
        "waznEnglish": "arises",
        "waznTlit": "shajar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَجَرَتَهَا",
        "answer": "its tree",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 757,
        "tlit": "shajaratahā",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "72",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَنْشَأْتُمْ شَجَرَتَهَا أَمْ نَحْنُ الْمُنْشِئُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَجَرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "arises",
        "waznTlit": "shajarat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَشْرَبُونَ",
        "answer": "you drink",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 763,
        "tlit": "tashrabūna",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "68",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ الْمَاءَ الَّذِي تَشْرَبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَرِبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to drink",
        "waznTlit": "shariba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شُرْبَ",
        "answer": "(as) drinking",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 763,
        "tlit": "shur'ba",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَشَارِبُونَ شُرْبَ الْهِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شُرْب",
        "waznEnglish": "and drink",
        "waznTlit": "shur'b",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَشَارِبُونَ",
        "answer": "And drink",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 763,
        "tlit": "fashāribūna",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "54",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَشَارِبُونَ عَلَيْهِ مِنَ الْحَمِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَّٰرِبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and drink",
        "waznTlit": "shāribīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَشَارِبُونَ",
        "answer": "And will drink",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 763,
        "tlit": "fashāribūna",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَشَارِبُونَ شُرْبَ الْهِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَّٰرِبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and drink",
        "waznTlit": "shāribīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَشْكُرُونَ",
        "answer": "then why are you not grateful",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 789,
        "tlit": "tashkurūna",
        "frequency": "75",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "70",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ نَشَاءُ جَعَلْنَاهُ أُجَاجًا فَلَوْلَا تَشْكُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَكَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be grateful, to give thanks",
        "waznTlit": "shakara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الشِّمَالِ",
        "answer": "(of) the left",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 798,
        "tlit": "l-shimāli",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَصْحَابُ الشِّمَالِ",
        "rootWord": "ش م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شِّمَال",
        "waznEnglish": "contains",
        "waznTlit": "shimāl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الشِّمَالِ",
        "answer": "(of) the left",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 798,
        "tlit": "l-shimāli",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَصْحَابُ الشِّمَالِ",
        "rootWord": "ش م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شِّمَال",
        "waznEnglish": "contains",
        "waznTlit": "shimāl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَشْتَهُونَ",
        "answer": "they desire",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 804,
        "tlit": "yashtahūna",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَحْمِ طَيْرٍ مِمَّا يَشْتَهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ه و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱشْتَهَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to desire",
        "waznTlit": "ish'tahat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَشَاءُ",
        "answer": "We willed",
        "pcklId": "211",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "nashāu",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "65",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ نَشَاءُ لَجَعَلْنَاهُ حُطَامًا فَظَلْتُمْ تَفَكَّهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَشَاءُ",
        "answer": "We willed",
        "pcklId": "212",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "nashāu",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "70",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ نَشَاءُ جَعَلْنَاهُ أُجَاجًا فَلَوْلَا تَشْكُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَصْحَابُ",
        "answer": "Then (the) companions",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "fa-aṣḥābu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَصْحَابُ الْمَيْمَنَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْحَابُ",
        "answer": "(are the) companions",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "aṣḥābu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَصْحَابُ الْمَيْمَنَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَصْحَابُ",
        "answer": "And (the) companions",
        "pcklId": "56",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "wa-aṣḥābu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَصْحَابُ الْمَشْأَمَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْحَابُ",
        "answer": "(are the) companions",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "aṣḥābu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَصْحَابُ الْمَشْأَمَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَصْحَابُ",
        "answer": "And (the) companions",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "wa-aṣḥābu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَصْحَابُ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْحَابُ",
        "answer": "(are the) companions",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "aṣḥābu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَصْحَابُ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِأَصْحَابِ",
        "answer": "For (the) companions",
        "pcklId": "60",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "li-aṣḥābi",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لِأَصْحَابِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَصْحَابُ",
        "answer": "And (the) companions",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "wa-aṣḥābu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَصْحَابُ الشِّمَالِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْحَابُ",
        "answer": "(are the) companions",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "aṣḥābu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَصْحَابُ الشِّمَالِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْحَابِ",
        "answer": "(the) companions",
        "pcklId": "63",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "aṣḥābi",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "90",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا إِنْ كَانَ مِنْ أَصْحَابِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْحَابِ",
        "answer": "(the) companions",
        "pcklId": "64",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "aṣḥābi",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "91",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَلَامٌ لَكَ مِنْ أَصْحَابِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُصَدَّعُونَ",
        "answer": "they will get headache",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 828,
        "tlit": "yuṣaddaʿūna",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يُصَدَّعُونَ عَنْهَا وَلَا يُنْزِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُصَدَّعُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to have headache",
        "waznTlit": "yuṣaddaʿu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُصَدِّقُونَ",
        "answer": "you admit the truth",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "tuṣaddiqūna",
        "frequency": "155",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "57",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " نَحْنُ خَلَقْنَاكُمْ فَلَوْلَا تُصَدِّقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَدَّقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to accept truth, to admit, to confirm, to believe",
        "waznTlit": "ṣaddaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَادِقِينَ",
        "answer": "truthful",
        "pcklId": "123",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "ṣādiqīna",
        "frequency": "155",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "87",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " تَرْجِعُونَهَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَادِق",
        "waznEnglish": "are true",
        "waznTlit": "ṣādiq",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُصِرُّونَ",
        "answer": "persisting",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 834,
        "tlit": "yuṣirrūna",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يُصِرُّونَ عَلَى الْحِنْثِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصَرُّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to persist",
        "waznTlit": "aṣarru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَصْلِيَةُ",
        "answer": "And burning",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 858,
        "tlit": "wataṣliyatu",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "94",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَصْلِيَةُ جَحِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَصْلِيَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and they will be burned",
        "waznTlit": "taṣliyat",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الضَّالُّونَ",
        "answer": "O those astray",
        "pcklId": "180",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "l-ḍālūna",
        "frequency": "191",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "51",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ إِنَّكُمْ أَيُّهَا الضَّالُّونَ الْمُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَآلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "he went astray (from)",
        "waznTlit": "ḍāll",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الضَّالِّينَ",
        "answer": "the astray",
        "pcklId": "186",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "l-ḍālīna",
        "frequency": "191",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "92",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا إِنْ كَانَ مِنَ الْمُكَذِّبِينَ الضَّالِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَآلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "he went astray (from)",
        "waznTlit": "ḍāll",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَطَلْحٍ",
        "answer": "And banana trees",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 919,
        "tlit": "waṭalḥin",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَطَلْحٍ مَنْضُودٍ",
        "rootWord": "ط ل ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ط ل ح",
        "waznEnglish": "And banana trees",
        "waznTlit": "ṭā lām ḥā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُطَهَّرُونَ",
        "answer": "the purified",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 928,
        "tlit": "l-muṭaharūna",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "79",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَمَسُّهُ إِلَّا الْمُطَهَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ط ه ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُطَهَّرُون",
        "waznEnglish": "they are cleansed",
        "waznTlit": "muṭahharūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَطُوفُ",
        "answer": "Will circulate",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 932,
        "tlit": "yaṭūfu",
        "frequency": "41",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَطُوفُ عَلَيْهِمْ وِلْدَانٌ مُخَلَّدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ط و ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَافَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to circulate, to go around",
        "waznTlit": "ṭāfa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "طَيْرٍ",
        "answer": "(of) fowls",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 937,
        "tlit": "ṭayrin",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَحْمِ طَيْرٍ مِمَّا يَشْتَهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ط ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "(that) flies",
        "waznTlit": "ṭayr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَظَلْتُمْ",
        "answer": "then you would remain",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 941,
        "tlit": "faẓaltum",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "65",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ نَشَاءُ لَجَعَلْنَاهُ حُطَامًا فَظَلْتُمْ تَفَكَّهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَلَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to continue, to remain",
        "waznTlit": "ẓalla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَظِلٍّ",
        "answer": "And shade",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 941,
        "tlit": "waẓillin",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَظِلٍّ مَمْدُودٍ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظِلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "and they were to continue",
        "waznTlit": "ẓill",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَظِلٍّ",
        "answer": "And a shade",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 941,
        "tlit": "waẓillin",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَظِلٍّ مِنْ يَحْمُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظِلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "and they were to continue",
        "waznTlit": "ẓill",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عُرُبًا",
        "answer": "Devoted",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 970,
        "tlit": "ʿuruban",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " عُرُبًا أَتْرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عُرُب",
        "waznEnglish": "the bedouins",
        "waznTlit": "ʿurub",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَظِيمِ",
        "answer": "the great",
        "pcklId": "97",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "l-ʿaẓīmi",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يُصِرُّونَ عَلَى الْحِنْثِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَظِيمِ",
        "answer": "the Most Great",
        "pcklId": "98",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "l-ʿaẓīmi",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "74",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَظِيمِ",
        "answer": "the Most Great",
        "pcklId": "99",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "l-ʿaẓīmi",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "96",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعِظَامًا",
        "answer": "and bones",
        "pcklId": "124",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "waʿiẓāman",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَقُولُونَ أَئِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَظِيمٌ",
        "answer": "great",
        "pcklId": "125",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "ʿaẓīmun",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "76",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّهُ لَقَسَمٌ لَوْ تَعْلَمُونَ عَظِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "you know",
        "pcklId": "337",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "taʿlamūna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "61",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَىٰ أَنْ نُبَدِّلَ أَمْثَالَكُمْ وَنُنْشِئَكُمْ فِي مَا لَا تَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلِمْتُمُ",
        "answer": "you know",
        "pcklId": "338",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿalim'tumu",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "62",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ عَلِمْتُمُ النَّشْأَةَ الْأُولَىٰ فَلَوْلَا تَذَكَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "you know ",
        "pcklId": "339",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "taʿlamūna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "76",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّهُ لَقَسَمٌ لَوْ تَعْلَمُونَ عَظِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) the worlds",
        "pcklId": "542",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "l-ʿālamīna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "80",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " تَنْزِيلٌ مِنْ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰلَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿālamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعْلُومٍ",
        "answer": "well-known",
        "pcklId": "850",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "maʿlūmin",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لَمَجْمُوعُونَ إِلَىٰ مِيقَاتِ يَوْمٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّعْلُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "maʿlūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْمَلُونَ",
        "answer": "do",
        "pcklId": "247",
        "rootWordId": 1022,
        "tlit": "yaʿmalūna",
        "frequency": "360",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " جَزَاءً بِمَا كَانُوا يَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَمِلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do, to work",
        "waznTlit": "ʿamila",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِينٌ",
        "answer": "(with) large eyes",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "ʿīnun",
        "frequency": "65",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَحُورٌ عِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "ʿīn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعِينٍ",
        "answer": "a flowing stream",
        "pcklId": "63",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "maʿīnin",
        "frequency": "65",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " بِأَكْوَابٍ وَأَبَارِيقَ وَكَأْسٍ مِنْ مَعِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّعِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "maʿīn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمُغْرَمُونَ",
        "answer": "surely are laden with debt",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1058,
        "tlit": "lamugh'ramūna",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "66",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا لَمُغْرَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُغْرَمُون",
        "waznEnglish": "inseparable",
        "waznTlit": "mugh'ramūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "غَيْرَ",
        "answer": "not",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 1095,
        "tlit": "ghayra",
        "frequency": "154",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "86",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَوْلَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ غَيْرَ مَدِينِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "so they will surely change",
        "waznTlit": "ghayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَفُرُشٍ",
        "answer": "And (on) couches",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1119,
        "tlit": "wafurushin",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفُرُشٍ مَرْفُوعَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ش",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فِرَٰش",
        "waznEnglish": "We have spread it",
        "waznTlit": "firāsh",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَفَكَّهُونَ",
        "answer": "wondering",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1150,
        "tlit": "tafakkahūna",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "65",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ نَشَاءُ لَجَعَلْنَاهُ حُطَامًا فَظَلْتُمْ تَفَكَّهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ك ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَفَكَّهُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to wonder",
        "waznTlit": "tafakkahu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَفَاكِهَةٍ",
        "answer": "And fruits",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1150,
        "tlit": "wafākihatin",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَاكِهَةٍ مِمَّا يَتَخَيَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ك ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَٰكِهَة",
        "waznEnglish": "wondering",
        "waznTlit": "fākihat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَفَاكِهَةٍ",
        "answer": "And fruit",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1150,
        "tlit": "wafākihatin",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَاكِهَةٍ كَثِيرَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ف ك ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَٰكِهَة",
        "waznEnglish": "wondering",
        "waznTlit": "fākihat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَبْلَ",
        "answer": "before",
        "pcklId": "272",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "qabla",
        "frequency": "294",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا قَبْلَ ذَٰلِكَ مُتْرَفِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَبْل",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "qabl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "answer": "facing each other",
        "pcklId": "292",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "mutaqābilīna",
        "frequency": "294",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " مُتَّكِئِينَ عَلَيْهَا مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّتَقَٰبِلِين",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "mutaqābilīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَدَّرْنَا",
        "answer": "[We] have decreed",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "qaddarnā",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "60",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " نَحْنُ قَدَّرْنَا بَيْنَكُمُ الْمَوْتَ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمَسْبُوقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to determine, to plot",
        "waznTlit": "qaddara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَقُرْآنٌ",
        "answer": "(is) surely, a Quran",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "laqur'ānun",
        "frequency": "88",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "77",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُ لَقُرْآنٌ كَرِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قُرْءَان",
        "waznEnglish": "is recited",
        "waznTlit": "qur'ān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Proper noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَقْرَبُ",
        "answer": "(are) nearer",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 1187,
        "tlit": "aqrabu",
        "frequency": "96",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "85",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَحْنُ أَقْرَبُ إِلَيْهِ مِنْكُمْ وَلَٰكِنْ لَا تُبْصِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَقْرَب",
        "waznEnglish": "[you two] approach",
        "waznTlit": "aqrab",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُقَرَّبُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) the nearest ones",
        "pcklId": "91",
        "rootWordId": 1187,
        "tlit": "l-muqarabūna",
        "frequency": "96",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أُولَٰئِكَ الْمُقَرَّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُقَرَّبُون",
        "waznEnglish": "[you two] approach",
        "waznTlit": "muqarrabūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form II) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُقَرَّبِينَ",
        "answer": "those brought near",
        "pcklId": "92",
        "rootWordId": 1187,
        "tlit": "l-muqarabīna",
        "frequency": "96",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "88",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا إِنْ كَانَ مِنَ الْمُقَرَّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُقَرَّبُون",
        "waznEnglish": "[you two] approach",
        "waznTlit": "muqarrabūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form II) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أُقْسِمُ",
        "answer": "I swear",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 1201,
        "tlit": "uq'simu",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "75",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا أُقْسِمُ بِمَوَاقِعِ النُّجُومِ",
        "rootWord": "ق س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَقْسَمُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to swear",
        "waznTlit": "aqsamu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَقَسَمٌ",
        "answer": "(is) surely an oath",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1201,
        "tlit": "laqasamun",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "76",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّهُ لَقَسَمٌ لَوْ تَعْلَمُونَ عَظِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَسَم",
        "waznEnglish": "distribute",
        "waznTlit": "qasam",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَقْطُوعَةٍ",
        "answer": "limited",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 1215,
        "tlit": "maqṭūʿatin",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا مَقْطُوعَةٍ وَلَا مَمْنُوعَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق ط ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَقْطُوعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and [they] cut",
        "waznTlit": "maqṭūʿat",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَلِيلٌ",
        "answer": "And a few",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 1225,
        "tlit": "waqalīlun",
        "frequency": "76",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَلِيلٌ مِنَ الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَلِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) little",
        "waznTlit": "qalīl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَقُولُونَ",
        "answer": "say",
        "pcklId": "1519",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "yaqūlūna",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَقُولُونَ أَئِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قُلْ",
        "answer": "Say",
        "pcklId": "1520",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qul",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "49",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قُلْ إِنَّ الْأَوَّلِينَ وَالْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قِيلًا",
        "answer": "a saying",
        "pcklId": "1623",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qīlan",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا قِيلًا سَلَامًا سَلَامًا",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "say",
        "waznTlit": "qīl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُقْوِينَ",
        "answer": "for the wayfarers in the desert",
        "pcklId": "41",
        "rootWordId": 1247,
        "tlit": "lil'muq'wīna",
        "frequency": "42",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "73",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " نَحْنُ جَعَلْنَاهَا تَذْكِرَةً وَمَتَاعًا لِلْمُقْوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُقْوِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) All-Strong",
        "waznTlit": "muq'wīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكَأْسٍ",
        "answer": "and a cup",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1250,
        "tlit": "wakasin",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " بِأَكْوَابٍ وَأَبَارِيقَ وَكَأْسٍ مِنْ مَعِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك أ س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك أ س",
        "waznEnglish": "a cup",
        "waznTlit": "kāf hamza sīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كِتَابٍ",
        "answer": "a Book",
        "pcklId": "283",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "kitābin",
        "frequency": "319",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "78",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي كِتَابٍ مَكْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِتَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "write",
        "waznTlit": "kitāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَثِيرَةٍ",
        "answer": "abundant",
        "pcklId": "163",
        "rootWordId": 1259,
        "tlit": "kathīratin",
        "frequency": "167",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَاكِهَةٍ كَثِيرَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَثِيرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "much ",
        "waznTlit": "kathīrat",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "answer": "deny",
        "pcklId": "162",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "tukadhibūna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "82",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَجْعَلُونَ رِزْقَكُمْ أَنَّكُمْ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَاذِبَةٌ",
        "answer": "a denial",
        "pcklId": "252",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kādhibatun",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَيْسَ لِوَقْعَتِهَا كَاذِبَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَٰذِب",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "kādhib",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "answer": "the deniers",
        "pcklId": "266",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "l-mukadhibūna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "51",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ إِنَّكُمْ أَيُّهَا الضَّالُّونَ الْمُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "the deniers",
        "pcklId": "267",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "l-mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "92",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا إِنْ كَانَ مِنَ الْمُكَذِّبِينَ الضَّالِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَرِيمٌ",
        "answer": "noble",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "karīmun",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "77",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُ لَقُرْآنٌ كَرِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَرِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "karīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَرِيمٍ",
        "answer": "pleasant",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "karīmin",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا بَارِدٍ وَلَا كَرِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَرِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "karīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَكْنُونٍ",
        "answer": "well-guarded",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1297,
        "tlit": "maknūnin",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "78",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي كِتَابٍ مَكْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّكْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "you conceal it",
        "waznTlit": "maknūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَكْنُونِ",
        "answer": "well-protected",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 1297,
        "tlit": "l-maknūni",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَمْثَالِ اللُّؤْلُؤِ الْمَكْنُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّكْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "you conceal it",
        "waznTlit": "maknūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِأَكْوَابٍ",
        "answer": "With vessels",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1301,
        "tlit": "bi-akwābin",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " بِأَكْوَابٍ وَأَبَارِيقَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك و ب",
        "waznEnglish": "and cups",
        "waznTlit": "kāf wāw bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَانَتْ",
        "answer": "So they become",
        "pcklId": "1245",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "fakānat",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَانَتْ هَبَاءً مُنْبَثًّا",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "And you will become",
        "pcklId": "1246",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "wakuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُنْتُمْ أَزْوَاجًا ثَلَاثَةً",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they used (to)",
        "pcklId": "1247",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " جَزَاءً بِمَا كَانُوا يَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "were",
        "pcklId": "1248",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا قَبْلَ ذَٰلِكَ مُتْرَفِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكَانُوا",
        "answer": "And were",
        "pcklId": "1249",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "wakānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يُصِرُّونَ عَلَى الْحِنْثِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكَانُوا",
        "answer": "And they used (to)",
        "pcklId": "1250",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "wakānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَقُولُونَ أَئِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكُنَّا",
        "answer": "and become",
        "pcklId": "1251",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "wakunnā",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَقُولُونَ أَئِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you are",
        "pcklId": "1252",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "86",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَوْلَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ غَيْرَ مَدِينِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you are",
        "pcklId": "1253",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "87",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " تَرْجِعُونَهَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "he was",
        "pcklId": "1254",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "88",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا إِنْ كَانَ مِنَ الْمُقَرَّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "he was",
        "pcklId": "1255",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "90",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا إِنْ كَانَ مِنْ أَصْحَابِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "he was",
        "pcklId": "1256",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "92",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا إِنْ كَانَ مِنَ الْمُكَذِّبِينَ الضَّالِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللُّؤْلُؤِ",
        "answer": "pearls",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1311,
        "tlit": "l-lu'lu-i",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَمْثَالِ اللُّؤْلُؤِ الْمَكْنُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ل أ ل أ",
        "rootWordType": "quadriliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل أ ل أ",
        "waznEnglish": "and pearl",
        "waznTlit": "lām hamza lām hamza",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَلَحْمِ",
        "answer": "And (the) flesh",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 1322,
        "tlit": "walaḥmi",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَحْمِ طَيْرٍ مِمَّا يَشْتَهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "and flesh",
        "waznTlit": "lām ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَغْوًا",
        "answer": "vain talk",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1336,
        "tlit": "laghwan",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسْمَعُونَ فِيهَا لَغْوًا وَلَا تَأْثِيمًا",
        "rootWord": "ل غ و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَغْو",
        "waznEnglish": "and make noise",
        "waznTlit": "laghū",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيْسَ",
        "answer": "Not",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 1363,
        "tlit": "laysa",
        "frequency": "89",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لَيْسَ لِوَقْعَتِهَا كَاذِبَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ي س",
        "waznEnglish": "to not be",
        "waznTlit": "lām yā sīn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَمَتَاعًا",
        "answer": "and a provision",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 1367,
        "tlit": "wamatāʿan",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "73",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " نَحْنُ جَعَلْنَاهَا تَذْكِرَةً وَمَتَاعًا لِلْمُقْوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م ت ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَتَٰع",
        "waznEnglish": "[then] I will grant him enjoyment",
        "waznTlit": "matāʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَأَمْثَالِ",
        "answer": "Like",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 1369,
        "tlit": "ka-amthāli",
        "frequency": "169",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَمْثَالِ اللُّؤْلُؤِ الْمَكْنُونِ",
        "rootWord": "م ث ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَثَل",
        "waznEnglish": "then he assumed for her the likeness",
        "waznTlit": "mathal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْثَالَكُمْ",
        "answer": "your likeness[es]",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 1369,
        "tlit": "amthālakum",
        "frequency": "169",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "61",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَىٰ أَنْ نُبَدِّلَ أَمْثَالَكُمْ وَنُنْشِئَكُمْ فِي مَا لَا تَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ث ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَثَل",
        "waznEnglish": "then he assumed for her the likeness",
        "waznTlit": "mathal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَمْدُودٍ",
        "answer": "extended",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 1379,
        "tlit": "mamdūdin",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَظِلٍّ مَمْدُودٍ",
        "rootWord": "م د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّمْدُود",
        "waznEnglish": "and prolongs them",
        "waznTlit": "mamdūd",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُزْنِ",
        "answer": "the rain clouds",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1390,
        "tlit": "l-muz'ni",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "69",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَنْزَلْتُمُوهُ مِنَ الْمُزْنِ أَمْ نَحْنُ الْمُنْزِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ز ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م ز ن",
        "waznEnglish": "the rain clouds",
        "waznTlit": "mīm zāy nūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَمَسُّهُ",
        "answer": "touch it",
        "pcklId": "53",
        "rootWordId": 1394,
        "tlit": "yamassuhu",
        "frequency": "61",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "79",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَمَسُّهُ إِلَّا الْمُطَهَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م س س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَسَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to touch",
        "waznTlit": "massa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَمَالِئُونَ",
        "answer": "Then will fill",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 1412,
        "tlit": "famāliūna",
        "frequency": "40",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَالِئُونَ مِنْهَا الْبُطُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ل أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَالِـُٔون",
        "waznEnglish": "surely, I will fill",
        "waznTlit": "māliūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَمْنُوعَةٍ",
        "answer": "forbidden",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 1418,
        "tlit": "mamnūʿatin",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا مَقْطُوعَةٍ وَلَا مَمْنُوعَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ن ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَمْنُوعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "prevents",
        "waznTlit": "mamnūʿat",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُمْنُونَ",
        "answer": "you emit",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1420,
        "tlit": "tum'nūna",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "58",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمْ مَا تُمْنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُمْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to emit",
        "waznTlit": "yum'nā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مِتْنَا",
        "answer": "we die",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "mit'nā",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَقُولُونَ أَئِذَا مِتْنَا وَكُنَّا تُرَابًا وَعِظَامًا أَإِنَّا لَمَبْعُوثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّاتَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to die",
        "waznTlit": "māta",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَوْتَ",
        "answer": "the death",
        "pcklId": "107",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "l-mawta",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "60",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " نَحْنُ قَدَّرْنَا بَيْنَكُمُ الْمَوْتَ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمَسْبُوقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَوْت",
        "waznEnglish": "(should) you die",
        "waznTlit": "mawt",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَمَاءٍ",
        "answer": "And water",
        "pcklId": "51",
        "rootWordId": 1428,
        "tlit": "wamāin",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَاءٍ مَسْكُوبٍ",
        "rootWord": "م و ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ه",
        "waznEnglish": "water",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw hā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَاءَ",
        "answer": "the water",
        "pcklId": "52",
        "rootWordId": 1428,
        "tlit": "l-māa",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "68",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ الْمَاءَ الَّذِي تَشْرَبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ه",
        "waznEnglish": "water",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw hā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "النُّجُومِ",
        "answer": "(of) the stars",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1444,
        "tlit": "l-nujūmi",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "75",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا أُقْسِمُ بِمَوَاقِعِ النُّجُومِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ج م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ج م",
        "waznEnglish": "the stars",
        "waznTlit": "nūn jīm mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُنْزِفُونَ",
        "answer": "they will get intoxicated",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1459,
        "tlit": "yunzifūna",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يُصَدَّعُونَ عَنْهَا وَلَا يُنْزِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ز ف",
        "waznEnglish": "to be intoxicated",
        "waznTlit": "nūn zāy fā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْزَلْتُمُوهُ",
        "answer": "who send it down",
        "pcklId": "241",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "anzaltumūhu",
        "frequency": "293",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "69",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَنْزَلْتُمُوهُ مِنَ الْمُزْنِ أَمْ نَحْنُ الْمُنْزِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنزَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send down, to reveal",
        "waznTlit": "anzala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُزُلُهُمْ",
        "answer": "(is) their hospitality",
        "pcklId": "266",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "nuzuluhum",
        "frequency": "293",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا نُزُلُهُمْ يَوْمَ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نُزُل",
        "waznEnglish": "it descended",
        "waznTlit": "nuzul",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَنُزُلٌ",
        "answer": "Then, hospitality",
        "pcklId": "267",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "fanuzulun",
        "frequency": "293",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "93",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَنُزُلٌ مِنْ حَمِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نُزُل",
        "waznEnglish": "it descended",
        "waznTlit": "nuzul",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَنْزِيلٌ",
        "answer": "A Revelation",
        "pcklId": "281",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "tanzīlun",
        "frequency": "293",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "80",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " تَنْزِيلٌ مِنْ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَنزِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "it descended",
        "waznTlit": "tanzīl",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُنْزِلُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) the Ones to send",
        "pcklId": "290",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "l-munzilūna",
        "frequency": "293",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "69",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَنْزَلْتُمُوهُ مِنَ الْمُزْنِ أَمْ نَحْنُ الْمُنْزِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنزِلِين",
        "waznEnglish": "it descended",
        "waznTlit": "munzilīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْشَأْنَاهُنَّ",
        "answer": "[We] have produced them",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1470,
        "tlit": "anshanāhunna",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْشَأْنَاهُنَّ إِنْشَاءً",
        "rootWord": "ن ش أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنشَأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to produce, to raise",
        "waznTlit": "ansha-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنُنْشِئَكُمْ",
        "answer": "and produce you",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1470,
        "tlit": "wanunshi-akum",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "61",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَىٰ أَنْ نُبَدِّلَ أَمْثَالَكُمْ وَنُنْشِئَكُمْ فِي مَا لَا تَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ش أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنشَأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to produce, to raise",
        "waznTlit": "ansha-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْشَأْتُمْ",
        "answer": "who produced",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1470,
        "tlit": "anshatum",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "72",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَنْشَأْتُمْ شَجَرَتَهَا أَمْ نَحْنُ الْمُنْشِئُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ش أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنشَأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to produce, to raise",
        "waznTlit": "ansha-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّشْأَةَ",
        "answer": "the creation",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 1470,
        "tlit": "l-nashata",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "62",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ عَلِمْتُمُ النَّشْأَةَ الْأُولَىٰ فَلَوْلَا تَذَكَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ش أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّشْأَة",
        "waznEnglish": "is brought up",
        "waznTlit": "nashat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِنْشَاءً",
        "answer": "(into) a creation",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1470,
        "tlit": "inshāan",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْشَأْنَاهُنَّ إِنْشَاءً",
        "rootWord": "ن ش أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنشَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "is brought up",
        "waznTlit": "inshā",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُنْشِئُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) the Producers",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 1470,
        "tlit": "l-munshiūna",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "72",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " أَأَنْتُمْ أَنْشَأْتُمْ شَجَرَتَهَا أَمْ نَحْنُ الْمُنْشِئُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ش أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنشِـُٔون",
        "waznEnglish": "is brought up",
        "waznTlit": "munshiūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَنْضُودٍ",
        "answer": "layered",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1482,
        "tlit": "manḍūdin",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَطَلْحٍ مَنْضُودٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ض د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّنضُود",
        "waznEnglish": "arranged",
        "waznTlit": "manḍūd",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَنْظُرُونَ",
        "answer": "look on",
        "pcklId": "77",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "tanẓurūna",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "84",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْتُمْ حِينَئِذٍ تَنْظُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّظَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to look, to see",
        "waznTlit": "naẓara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّعِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) Pleasure",
        "pcklId": "130",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "l-naʿīmi",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي جَنَّاتِ النَّعِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَعِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "naʿīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَعِيمٍ",
        "answer": "(of) Pleasure",
        "pcklId": "131",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "naʿīmin",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "89",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَوْحٌ وَرَيْحَانٌ وَجَنَّتُ نَعِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَعِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "naʿīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّارَ",
        "answer": "the Fire",
        "pcklId": "124",
        "rootWordId": 1529,
        "tlit": "l-nāra",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "71",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ النَّارَ الَّتِي تُورُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَار",
        "waznEnglish": "a fire",
        "waznTlit": "nār",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "هَبَاءً",
        "answer": "dust particles",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1540,
        "tlit": "habāan",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَانَتْ هَبَاءً مُنْبَثًّا",
        "rootWord": "ه ب و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ه ب و",
        "waznEnglish": "(as) dust",
        "waznTlit": "hā bā wāw",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْهِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) the thirsty camels",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1576,
        "tlit": "l-hīmi",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَشَارِبُونَ شُرْبَ الْهِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ه ي م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] roam",
        "waznTlit": "hīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُورُونَ",
        "answer": "you ignite",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1604,
        "tlit": "tūrūna",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "71",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ النَّارَ الَّتِي تُورُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تُورُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ignite",
        "waznTlit": "tūru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَوْضُونَةٍ",
        "answer": "decorated",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1622,
        "tlit": "mawḍūnatin",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَىٰ سُرُرٍ مَوْضُونَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ض ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ض ن",
        "waznEnglish": "decorated",
        "waznTlit": "wāw ḍād nūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "مِيقَاتِ",
        "answer": "(the) appointment",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1635,
        "tlit": "mīqāti",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَمَجْمُوعُونَ إِلَىٰ مِيقَاتِ يَوْمٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِيقَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "are gathered to their appointed time",
        "waznTlit": "mīqāt",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَعَتِ",
        "answer": "occurs",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1639,
        "tlit": "waqaʿati",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا وَقَعَتِ الْوَاقِعَةُ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَقَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fall, to occur, to fulfill",
        "waznTlit": "waqaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِمَوَاقِعِ",
        "answer": "by setting",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 1639,
        "tlit": "bimawāqiʿi",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "75",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا أُقْسِمُ بِمَوَاقِعِ النُّجُومِ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَوَٰقِع",
        "waznEnglish": "(became) incumbent",
        "waznTlit": "mawāqiʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِوَقْعَتِهَا",
        "answer": "at its occurrence",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 1639,
        "tlit": "liwaqʿatihā",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَيْسَ لِوَقْعَتِهَا كَاذِبَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَقْعَت",
        "waznEnglish": "(became) incumbent",
        "waznTlit": "waqʿat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْوَاقِعَةُ",
        "answer": "the Event",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 1639,
        "tlit": "l-wāqiʿatu",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا وَقَعَتِ الْوَاقِعَةُ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَاقِعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(became) incumbent",
        "waznTlit": "wāqiʿat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُتَّكِئِينَ",
        "answer": "Reclining",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1642,
        "tlit": "muttakiīna",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " مُتَّكِئِينَ عَلَيْهَا مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "و ك أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُتَّكِـِٔين",
        "waznEnglish": "I lean",
        "waznTlit": "muttakiīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وِلْدَانٌ",
        "answer": "boys",
        "pcklId": "93",
        "rootWordId": 1647,
        "tlit": "wil'dānun",
        "frequency": "102",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَطُوفُ عَلَيْهِمْ وِلْدَانٌ مُخَلَّدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ل د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَلِيد",
        "waznEnglish": "Shall I bear a child",
        "waznTlit": "walīd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَقِينِ",
        "answer": "certain",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 1660,
        "tlit": "l-yaqīni",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "95",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ هَٰذَا لَهُوَ حَقُّ الْيَقِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي ق ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "firmly believe",
        "waznTlit": "yaqīn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَيْمَنَةِ",
        "answer": "(of) the right",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "l-maymanati",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَصْحَابُ الْمَيْمَنَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَيْمَنَة",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "maymanat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَيْمَنَةِ",
        "answer": "(of) the right",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "l-maymanati",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَصْحَابُ الْمَيْمَنَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَيْمَنَة",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "maymanat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَمِينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the right",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "l-yamīni",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَصْحَابُ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "yamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَمِينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the right",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "l-yamīni",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَصْحَابُ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "yamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَمِينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the right",
        "pcklId": "56",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "l-yamīni",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لِأَصْحَابِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "yamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَمِينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the right",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "l-yamīni",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "90",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا إِنْ كَانَ مِنْ أَصْحَابِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "yamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَمِينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the right",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "l-yamīni",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "91",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَلَامٌ لَكَ مِنْ أَصْحَابِ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "yamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمٍ",
        "answer": "(of) a Day",
        "pcklId": "277",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmin",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَمَجْمُوعُونَ إِلَىٰ مِيقَاتِ يَوْمٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(on the) Day",
        "pcklId": "278",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "56",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا نُزُلُهُمْ يَوْمَ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    }
]